Wow.
Well. you were right.
It's amazing.
Was all that junk there
when you were little?
No. Just the woods.
Ah. so is that a thing
in the Finnish countryside?
Just throw all your rubbish
in the woods?
No.
Well. maybe a little.
-Aah!
-Oh. yes!
I need to... I need to
carry you through.
Yeah. Ohh!
Aah! Ohh!
Huh.
Okay.
This is. uh...
Yeah.
-Yes?
-Yeah.
This is gonna be
a bit more work.
And a bit of fixing.
Patching up.
Put some carpet down there.
Have plenty of time after work.
I... wanna show you something.
This used to be
my and Taru's bedroom
when we spent the summers
here with Grandma.
There was this...
lovely green wallpaper.
It's still here!
Oh. wow.
Hmm.
Well...
we did want nature close by.
-This is...
-We'll get rid of it.
Look.
There used to be
an armchair here
for reading bedtime stories.
And then a dollhouse over here.
This lovely old rocking horse
over here.
And then we can put
the crib for the baby here.
There's definitely enough room.
For all three kids.
And...
What about London?
Fuck London.
Hmm.
-Yeah!
Whoa!
Whoo!
Saga?
Jesus.
Saga!
Oh. my God!
Listen.
As you shout.
so will the forest answer.
What?
It's a saying in Finland.
I used to sneak here in secret.
Why?
Grandma forbid me to come.
The forest takes its own.
Ohh. Really?
Make me a mother.
A lot of patching up.
Is she all right?
What is this?
Is it alright?
W-What's happening?
What is happening?
What's the matter with it?
What's happening?
What's wrong with it?
Shh.
I was so worried.
These are for you.
Is he okay?
Yeah. Yeah. He's. uh...
You're both fine.
I want to see him.
Okay.
Yeah. Wait.
Bring him here.
I want to hold him.
He won't break.
Oh. yeah. I know.
I can show you.
You can hold him like this.
And into Mommy's arms.
-Scooch.
-Yeah.
Daddy is like a support network
at this stage.
Yeah...
Mummy's hug calms down.
Never seen such a hairy baby.
Is this...
You have a healthy baby boy.
You had a pretty
difficult birth. so you
can get therapy if...
No. everything's all right.
I'm totally fine.
What's that?
Nothing.
Everything is good.
-Okay.
-Get the flowers.
-Oh.
Yeah.
Eh. Take another one.
Wait. darling.
I can... I can help.
No. no. I'm good.
This is where it all begins.
Us.
Here we go.
It's your new home.
Look how Daddy's
renovated it all for you.
-Jon. He's hungry.
-Upstairs.
Down there's the kitchen.
Oh. look at this.
Big window.
And this is
a very special room...
Mummy's made just for you.
With lots of love.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Shh.
Mummy's little darling.
you'll get some food soon.
Darling.
Yes.
There.
Ow!
Oh. Does it hurt?
No. No. no.
You okay?
Yeah.
Remember what the midwife said.
Eye contact is crucial.
Yeah.
Maybe upholstery's a bit off.
Let me just get this up.
I... I know how to do this.
Is the nipple hitting
the roof of the mouth?
Just...
Stop it!
It's... Sorry.
Mummy's sweetheart. hi!
Careful! He could fall!
It hurts me when I touch.
I'm your daddy. We're not
gonna hurt you. are we?
That's it.
There we go. That's better.
It's like a tiny
little tail sprout.
That's cute.
Better?
Good evening. good night.
With roses adorned.
With carnations covered.
Slip under the covers
Early tomorrow. so God willing.
You will wake once again
Early tomorrow...
What... What if
you stop singing?
I'm doing my best.
I know.
I'm... I'm just trying to help.
Yeah. but he doesn't
want to sleep.
No. he just doesn't
wanna sleep alone. do ya?
That's better now. isn't it?
He's lifting his head up.
How's he doing that?
Oh. you're such a little
miracle. Christian. aren't you?
Does he look like
a Christian to you?
Saga.
Just put him
into those party clothes now!
So nice that you came.
Saga?
-Mother.
-Surprise!
-We came to help you.
-Hi!
We couldn't wait
to see the little prince!
-And a lovely dress!
-Thank you.
You look really tired.
I'm fine.
Your button is undone.
It's okay.
It's still a bit unfinished
as the baby was born early.
there wasn't time.
But when it's all done.
the view out will be beautiful.
Was it necessary to do all this
with you so exhausted?
Hey. it's really beautiful.
-Wow!
-Look. Anna!
What a dream room
Auntie has made!
-Isn't it fine?
-Yes!
-Isn't this wallpaper...
-Just like when we were kids.
It's lovely.
When will you go back to work?
Uh...
I'm taking five years off.
-What?
-Yeah.
We'll have two more babies.
Kids are small
for such a short time.
If you miss
all those lovely moments.
you can't get them back.
Yes. but...
Yeah. he's not very happy
at the moment.
I have a sleeve.
Should we try?
Oh. yeah.
-Clothes hurt him.
-You little darling!
Come here now.
You're a big boy!
Let's give you to your grandma.
Careful. he's a bit heavy.
-Who do we have here...
-I can take it...
I didn't kill you two either.
Sounds like he's hungry.
Has he eaten?
Yes. he's eaten.
Why on Earth did you want
to move in to this wilderness?
I got it wrong.
Oh. We just... We just wanted
him to grow up around nature.
I know that Saga always liked
more trees than people.
What do you mean?
What was that?
No. Saga was a bit
antisocial as a kid.
You always said
your friends laughed at you
for being so weird.
Let go!
Ohh!
Mother! Help!
I'll call an ambulance.
Get my doctor's bag.
Are you okay?
I don't know how it could
yank so hard.
-I wasn't holding him wrong.
-I didn't mean that.
I've been wondering if there's
something wrong with it.
I don't think
babies should be like that.
You were just like that
as a baby.
-Are you staying the night?
-Overnight flight to Boston.
The lectures begin.
Weren't you supposed
to be retired?
I just don't happen to be
a bun-baking granny
sacrificing all their time
to grandchildren.
So you didn't get that
from Grandma.
You have a really romanticised
idea of how people should be.
Hi! So nice that you came!
-Congratulations!
-Thank you!
-Are you okay?
-Yeah. I am.
Congratulations!
Gets a bit lost. but...
There he is!
He's a bit of
a crybaby now but...
-Strong lungs. at least!
-That's right.
Loud enough. Congratulations!
Mum. Let's go.
Yeah.
I'll calm him down a bit here.
But so lovely that you came.
See you in a minute!
Why did it look so weird?
Shh!
No. I'm. uh.
director of sustainability.
Get me an earlier ticket.
No. No. no. no. For tonight.
Yes. yes. Tonight.
-Babies are usually cute.
-Yeah.
She chose the dress herself.
Shh. shh. shh. shh.
Shh. shh. shh. shh. shh.
I can take Christian.
He wants to be in the dark.
Well...
He's kind of why
they're all here.
Ohh.
Yeah.
Dear friends.
Thank you all for coming.
Most of you have been
absolutely lovely.
Others. a little bit Finnish.
In a good way.
Unfortunately. my father.
due to illness.
he can't make it
and bless our child.
But he will be
very pleased to hear
that our baby's name is...
Kuura.
What?
His name is Kuura.
I just felt a little sick. But
so lovely that you came!
Bye!
Now first of all.
you take care of yourself.
That's the most important thing.
You should know.
Bye!
You're mad at me.
I think Kuura is a...
beautiful name.
But we have to
do this together. okay?
We have to be us...
or none of this makes sense.
It makes me feel bad
when you just decide something
and then ride right over me.
I do everything wrong
all the time.
That's not what I'm saying.
Why are you correcting
every single thing I do?
I can't do anything right.
You made us a beautiful baby.
I'm just... trying to help.
Then stop instructing me...
telling me to do this
and not to do that.
You could just...
praise me sometimes.
And I am sorry about the name.
Hey.
Why don't you want
to kiss me anymore?
What? I do. All the time.
But you don't.
Okay.
This is all new and weird
for both of us.
But you are the best mum
in the world.
There's something wrong with it.
"Him." You mean "him."
He's just a bit sensitive
to sunlight.
He'll be fine.
Saga!
Hey!
Shh!
What are you doing?
Hey. you mustn't
rattle him like that!
Shh! Shh. shh. shh. shh!
Now it sleeps.
It doesn't sleep at all
at nights.
Hi!
-Look.
-Yeah.
You can move around
much better already.
What did the doctors say?
They said I am fully healed.
That's lovely!
Isn't it?
I'm still pig ugly.
Hey. nonsense!
Why do you say that for?
Everything is really
fine now. right?
Yeah.
Who's awake now?
Will you smile for Auntie?
-It never smiles.
-Good!
It's a bit strange.
Hey. darling!
Look. he's smiling. Yes!
-Good.
-That's just a grimace.
It isn't! Look at it! Good!
I'm looking.
What was that?
Hey. Anna!
Ugh. It's so awful.
Yeah. I'm just trying to...
Just making a pile over here.
Okay.
Did I ever tell you
what Granny said
right towards the end?
She called me. went on and on
about all this junk.
saying it kept "them" away
or something.
Keeps out the neighbors?
How very Finnish.
No. Cold iron.
"Cold iron burns them."
She lived in a world of her own.
Poor thing.
Don't.
Are you still in pain?
Is it asleep?
Please call him "him."
We don't have to do anything.
Just thought I'd be nice.
Or nasty.
You're beautiful.
I love you.
Look! It's sitting!
No. Come on.
Babies can't sit at that age.
Oh. yeah.
Stop it!
Sorry. I just...
You need rest.
So go to sleep.
Leave him. I don't mind.
I'll handle it.
Shh. shh.
MUM
Well. hi!
Finally you answered.
Saga!
Oh. hi.
I forgot it's night there.
Isn't Kuura sleeping yet?
Well.
You were a night owl like him
when you were little.
You had something to say?
I had?
Yes. you tried to call.
Saga!
Um...
Did Grandma ever say anything
about this forest?
The forest?
She always said there's
something dangerous in it.
That's one of her stories.
She believed
there were some... whatever.
Saga?
You been able to sleep at all?
Let Jon put Kuura to bed
for a change.
You must get some sleep.
Yeah. everything is fine.
Saga!
Saga? Saga?
What have you done?
There was...
What?
The floor. It was rotten and...
How has that tree grown back?
Kuura. He was calling it.
Okay.
I think that's something
we can talk with
the child-health clinic about.
I just want to know
what this is.
Exactly. We'll get some help.
Go ahead. I'll be fine.
How briskly
you wave your arms about!
You're such a tall
and heavy boy.
Your boy is perfectly healthy.
Sorry. Uh. like I said
before. my Finnish...
I'm sorry.
Shouldn't you examine this?
You can put his clothes on now.
I can dress him.
No. He's quiet now.
Don't touch him.
It'll scream
the moment you try to dress it.
He may have
some sensory defensiveness.
And perhaps a bit...
Yes. Each baby is different.
He is exceptionally
well developed
and really big for his age!
Good. strong muscles.
Like an ape.
Yeah. when he was born.
he had hair all over him.
That's quite normal.
But. um...
He sucked my blood.
It could be he's so hungry.
he sucks whatever
he can get into his mouth.
Well. you can tell
when he's hungry
if you watch his face closely.
You have probably
seen those little...
sucking lip movements.
And that's when
you can start feeding.
Right. Okay. Yeah.
You've been under pressure?
No. I'm alright.
But that's not the issue.
The problem is this baby.
Or how you feel about him.
All these difficult emotions
are perfectly normal.
But the fact is. the baby feels
better when you feel better.
I could make
a referral for you. Saga.
And you can make an appointment
to talk about things.
Thank you.
And the father is alright?
Yeah. Um. well. I mean...
Sometimes the early days
with a small baby
can be surprisingly hard.
especially for the mother.
No. I understand that.
For a lot of moms.
this new creature
can feel completely alien.
That went well. I guess.
I won't breastfeed him anymore.
-You mean... Wait.
-Never again.
If you're struggling
to bond with Kuura...
He sucks me dry.
That's why breastfeeding
is so important for you!
You're not even listening!
Babe. I am.
I am. okay?
I'm just trying to s...
-I want...
-To sa...
-I understand.
-you to stop!
You're completely exhausted.
I get it.
Your problem is...
That child!
No.
Your problem is your
relationship with our child.
What you're feeling is...
Don't tell me how I feel!
Of course they're early.
Who?
My parents.
We talked about this.
When?
Hey! Hello.
It's so lovely to see you!
Oh. is this the baby?
Oh. yeah. he's just sleeping...
-Oh.
-Son.
Dad.
Ooh. Hello...
Ooh! Steady. love!
Let's get some light on.
shall we?
He's a bit sensitive to light.
It's the child that ought to
learn from you. you know.
Just let people
raise their own children.
Oh!
So lovely to see you. Saga.
Welcome.
I'm so sorry about this mess.
The baby came early. and
we haven't found the time to...
Oh. never you mind.
Christian. shall
we give them the. um...
-Oh. yes. yeah.
-For the housewarming.
Ooh.
Ta-da!
-Wow.
Made him myself.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Right. well. uh. shall we
finally bless the child?
I'll go and get him. then.
Yes. please.
I read that local tales here say
that if you don't bless a child.
the trolls will take them.
-Ohh.
-Do people still believe that?
-No. Not anymore.
-That's why some families
still have troll blood
running through their veins.
Oh. Here's the little darling.
Lucky for you. those old trolls
are afraid of holy water.
So we can still save you.
Sanctify this water by the
power of the Holy Spirit...
so that they may be cleansed
and born again.
Now. what happened
with the name?
Oh. we...
Your father took it pretty hard.
Not that he'll say a word. mind.
Almighty God. Heavenly Father.
we ask you to bless this child
in the name of Jesus Christ.
In the name of the Father...
and of the Son...
and of the Holy Spirit.
-Amen.
Amen.
Ooh.
Yeah. That's better.
Is that...?
Yeah. yeah.
The seeds you gave me.
-Ohh!
-They're taking really well.
You've got some pumpkin
growing and some courgette.
Yeah.
And some beetroot here.
-And kale.
-And is the soil good?
Yeah. It's taken
a bit of work. but it's...
Well. it's certainly
all looking beautiful.
How did this get here?
Are you alright. dear?
Yes. This just... grew.
Makes no sense.
That's nature. Jon.
You can't fight it.
For me.
it was almost meditative.
doing all the household work
with little Jon.
-He was such a happy baby.
-Oh. Mum!
Well. you were...
my little sunshine.
Kuura doesn't really smile.
Well. of course.
every baby is different.
but we raise them with our love.
It really is the greatest
happiness in the world
to be a mother.
Don't you think?
It wasn't even hot!
What did you do?
What the hell did you do?
There is no fire.
It wasn't even near
the fireplace.
Just for once. can you just
think about what you're doing?!
It's just... cold.
It's cold iron.
I know what you are.
Drink.
Hey. babe!
Us.
All three.
Oh.
How's the formula going down?
Oh...
You know. he actually slurps up
as much as he can get.
-Wow.
-Yeah.
Great.
Maybe now I can feed him. too.
So it doesn't just fall on you.
Yeah.
I think it's better I feed him.
At least for now.
Okay.
How was work?
Yeah. Good. Just...
so Finnish.
What?
When is the last time
I asked you anything like...
"Did you have a good day?"
This is terrible.
Hmm. Wow.
The first year is the worst.
Yeah.
Divorce rates off the scale.
You haven't thought about
anything like that. have you?
-What? Divorce?
-Yeah.
No. Of course not.
I tell you everything.
You tell me everything. yeah?
Yeah.
You remember how we were saying
we were gonna start
on another one about now?
Can you imagine
being pregnant now?
Yeah.
I'm joking.
It'll come...
when it's time.
Yeah. Yeah.
By the way.
when's your appointment?
-Appointment?
-Yeah. The referral.
The children's
health-clinic thing.
You didn't book it.
I feel so bad when you tell
everyone I've got problems.
Yeah. we do have problems.
I don't want you
to speak for me.
That was the whole point.
that you could
speak for yourself.
I'm telling you now.
You could trust me at least
a bit and give me some space.
That's what
I've been trying to do!
Don't correct me!
Stop interfering!
Space. Okay.
Jon.
Jon! Jon!
Hah!
MUM
Hi! Where are you?
-It's Kuura.
-What?
-What's that noise?
-It's Kuura!
Who else has he mauled already?
Hey. is everything alright?
-You never ask that.
-Well. I'm asking now.
Yes.
Or I'm just...
Sometimes I think
I'm going to kill that child
if it doesn't get me first.
You know. I thought exactly
the same when you were little.
You did?
Yes. this one time
I was so tired of your screaming
that I left you outside a shop
and drove away.
Well. I drove back
and took you with me.
But at the time I had the
feeling you were sucking me dry.
You were just a terrible child.
They always say
that the wonderful moments
make up for the hard ones
many times over.
But I wouldn't be so sure.
Go away! Go away!
Saga. what's happening?
Saga!
Where have you been?
Where's Kuura's clothes?!
He'll freeze to death!
Get inside.
Looking for this?
Just please tell me
you have an explanation.
-It won't drink milk.
-Neither do I!
W-What are you gonna do.
start putting blood in my tea?!
No. You are not giving another
drop of blood to our son.
It won't take anything else.
-Saga. please.
-Give it to me.
-Let go!
-Give it to me!
Saga!
I don't know
who you are anymore.
If I don't give it blood.
it'll suck it out of me.
It'll kill me.
I don't know if I'm more afraid
for you or for Kuura.
So what do you want to do?
Pick a day.
Go into town.
Go... Go and see some friends.
Get yourself better.
While I take care of Kuura.
I want you to see...
you don't have to
destroy yourself... or us.
I want you to be happy again.
For us to be happy together.
Me too.
How are you?
How's work?
I've missed you.
Hey. there's the Mum!
She's enjoyed the nesting life
while we've slaved away!
We want to see photos!
I don't really have
too many good ones.
I so remember that.
no time to snap away.
All we have
are some terrible blurry pics.
-I'll take the vegetarian menu.
-It's really. really good.
So. how's work?
No. no talk about work!
Your life is much
more important!
Show us at least one pic.
this is not an official event.
I so remember that being
the best time of my life.
Yeah!
We just talked
about how nice you always were.
-Thank you.
-But then I suddenly realised.
None of us really knows you.
you know?
Maybe it's the Boss Role.
I've actually missed work a lot.
Hey. been there.
The sense of duty knocking.
Your stand-in guy has
actually been quite good.
Are you allergic?
-Did you have the shrimp?
-No. the vegetarian menu.
-Nuts?
-I've got to go.
Hey!
Hey.
Hey. Alright. Yeah. Okay.
What happened?
Are you okay? Talk to me.
Anyway. just trying
to support Saga.
She's still having
a pretty rough time.
What about you?
Like. deep down.
Was just...
I was so looking forward
to being a family.
Ohh.
Being a dad.
You're doing great.
I'm always away.
I don't know
what's going on here.
I think Saga is just exhausted.
I think it's something
more than that.
Nice.
Juice for madam.
Thanks...
Um...
Anna. go and play
with your cousin Kuura.
No!
It's not safe.
Shut the fuck up!
I'm gonna go and. uh...
shovel some snow.
Mother.
It's all right.
Hi.
It's just awful.
we still haven't got those boxes
unpacked.
I so hoped for a lovely and nice
little girl like Anna.
But instead...
I got that monster.
Studies say that if you don't
show empathy to your child
during the first three years.
he may never learn it.
I've given that thing
absolutely everything.
Right.
It just takes and takes and
takes.
Soon there'll be nothing left of
me.
But I can't be without it.
And I don't see the sense in
that.
And where's the happiness?
Things don't always go as
planned.
I just wanted our kids to have
what we had.
You're really living in a
reality all your own.
You think I really had fun
playing with you as a child?
Everything had to be
on your terms. and no matter
how shitty you acted
you were the one who needed to
be understood.
And it's still the same.
Mum called me to ask how you and
Kuura are doing.
But nothing about me or Anna.
Because we
must be doing really great.
You're still making
such a big deal of your
problems and emotions
that there's no room for the
rest of us.
Now you've moved on to
smothering your own child!
There's nothing wrong with
Kuura!
It's you who's making your
family life unbearable!
No one else!
Anna!
Hey! Hey!
Darling.
it's alright! Show me.
Let me see!
Saga. just leave it!
It's alright. we'll take you to
a hospital.
Taru?
You're the monster!
Ahhh!
Ah!
Wah. wah. wah.
Ah. ah.
Ah!
Wah. wah.
Whee!
That wasn't so bad. was it?
Look at him. all dressed up.
Now we can have a nice old
proper family dinner.
Let's get you in here.
Let me just get your leg
through there.
Have you spoken to Taru yet?
Anna's doing better.
If you're interested. that is.
But her finger
is gonna remain a stump.
What do you want from me?
Kuura. let's teach you
some table manners.
Okay?
Ah. Kuura.
Say "please."
Here comes the airplane.
Starting from now...
we're gonna
raise this child right.
So I'm setting some limits.
Human limits.
Right.
Here comes the airplane.
It's as much my fault
as it is yours.
Ohh.
Okay.
Here comes...
the airplane.
Wheeeeee.
The metal hurts him!
Oh. will you just give
your fucking fantasies a rest?!
Sorry. Kuura.
Mommy and Daddy are
just having a little argument.
It's all gonna be fine.
Here comes the airplane.
This child...
can't be raised.
Don't say that.
There's nothing
you can do about it.
You're wrong.
I'll prove you wrong.
Let it eat.
"Him"!
I'm not just gonna stand here
and watch you turn him
into a monster.
Leave it alooooone!
It's asleep.
I should apologize.
Okay.
I guess...
for many things.
Thank you.
For what?
For showing me
who you really are.
It's just. it's been too hard.
-Kuura is...
-You're right.
But not Kuura.
You.
What?
I always wanted a big family.
And then we met.
And I could see
our entire future.
Me too.
But you killed it.
And now it's like
I can't feel anything anymore.
It's like this impossibly heavy
weight is pushing me down.
Just because you feel bad
for being away so much.
You should never
have been a mother.
You hate our child.
You've turned him
completely dysfunctional.
I don't think you know
how to love.
I don't think you can love
anyone.
I don't need to listen to this.
You never listen to anyone.
You're so utterly.
blindingly selfish.
Taru was right.
You're the monster.
And I'm taking Kuura away
from you.
What?
He still has a chance to be
a perfectly normal boy.
He just needs professional help.
So do you.
You're not taking him.
I'm saving our child.
I've already spoken
to my parents.
It's done.
-Let go.
-And I'm gonna get full custody.
Let go!
You're hurting him!